<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Projects on MahdiKhadem</title><link>https://mahdikhadem.com/projects/</link><description>Recent content in Projects on MahdiKhadem</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mahdikhadem.com/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Computer Vision–Based Intraoperative Measurement of Biliopancreatic Limb Length</title><link>https://mahdikhadem.com/projects/project-bpll/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mahdikhadem.com/projects/project-bpll/</guid><description>A pilot study evaluating whether computer vision can replace subjective visual estimation of biliopancreatic limb (BPL) length during gastric bypass surgery with objective, calibrated intraoperative measurements.</description></item><item><title>Diagnostic Delay and Clinical Course of Pemphigus Vulgaris: An Iranian Cohort Study</title><link>https://mahdikhadem.com/projects/project-pemphigus/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mahdikhadem.com/projects/project-pemphigus/</guid><description>A cross-sectional clinical study examining presentation patterns, diagnostic delays, and treatment outcomes in patients with pemphigus vulgaris, highlighting systemic barriers to early diagnosis.</description></item><item><title>Effects of Metabolic and Bariatric Surgery on Serum Uric Acid, Renal Function, and Visceral Adiposity</title><link>https://mahdikhadem.com/projects/project-uricacid/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mahdikhadem.com/projects/project-uricacid/</guid><description>A comprehensive systematic review and meta-analysis examining how metabolic and bariatric surgery (MBS) affects serum uric acid over time, and how these changes relate to renal function and visceral adiposity.</description></item><item><title>M.D. Thesis: Neuroimaging–Cognition Relationships in Frontotemporal Dementia Using Routine Clinical MRI</title><link>https://mahdikhadem.com/projects/project-1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mahdikhadem.com/projects/project-1/</guid><description>An M.D. thesis project investigating structural neuroimaging correlates of cognitive impairment in frontotemporal dementia (FTD), with a focus on extracting meaningful information from low-resolution routine clinical MRI data.</description></item><item><title>PERSiMED: PERSian Intelligent MEDical Document Reader :A Smart NLP-based Framework for Persian Medical Documents</title><link>https://mahdikhadem.com/projects/project-6/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mahdikhadem.com/projects/project-6/</guid><description>A deep learning–based framework for intelligent extraction, semantic understanding, and structured digitization of Persian medical documents, designed to automate health insurance workflows and fraud detection.</description></item><item><title>Post-Bariatric Weight Trajectory Modelling and Clinical Prediction</title><link>https://mahdikhadem.com/projects/project-weightlosstrajectory/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mahdikhadem.com/projects/project-weightlosstrajectory/</guid><description>A data-driven project that models long-term postoperative weight trajectories after bariatric surgery and translates these patterns into clinically interpretable, patient-level predictions.</description></item><item><title>Retrieval-Augmented Clinical Question Answering for Bariatric Surgery</title><link>https://mahdikhadem.com/projects/project-5/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mahdikhadem.com/projects/project-5/</guid><description>A retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) system that uses the ASMBS bariatric surgery textbook as a knowledge base to answer medical questions with higher accuracy and fewer hallucinations than general-purpose AI models.</description></item><item><title>SnapExplain</title><link>https://mahdikhadem.com/projects/project-7/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mahdikhadem.com/projects/project-7/</guid><description>SnapExplain is an Android utility that brings large language model (LLM) explanations directly into your reading workflow.It integrates with Android’s native text-selection menu, allowing users to highlight any sentence in a PDF, ebook, or article and receive an instant, contextual explanation — without leaving the app they’re reading in.</description></item><item><title>Unveiling Predictors of Hypoalbuminemia Following One Anastomosis Gastric Bypass (OAGB): A Retrospective Analysis</title><link>https://mahdikhadem.com/projects/project-8/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mahdikhadem.com/projects/project-8/</guid><description>A machine learning-based clinical scoring system designed to predict hypoalbuminemia risk following One-Anastomosis Gastric Bypass (OAGB) surgery, enabling early intervention and personalized patient care.</description></item><item><title>ApoE Genotype–Specific Hippocampal Shape Alterations in Alzheimer’s Disease</title><link>https://mahdikhadem.com/projects/project-3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:33:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mahdikhadem.com/projects/project-3/</guid><description>A neuroimaging study investigating how hippocampal subfield structure and shape differ across ApoE genotypes, using high-resolution MRI and computational geometry–based morphometric analysis.</description></item><item><title>Post-Thesis: Advanced Neuroimaging Analysis Using GenAI</title><link>https://mahdikhadem.com/projects/project-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:33:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mahdikhadem.com/projects/project-2/</guid><description>An ongoing research effort to improve brain MRI reconstruction techniques, enabling large-scale neurodegeneration studies using routine clinical imaging data rather than relying solely on high-resolution research scans.</description></item></channel></rss>