<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>MahdiKhadem</title><link>https://mahdikhadem.com/</link><description>Recent content on MahdiKhadem</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mahdikhadem.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A tragedy - part 1</title><link>https://mahdikhadem.com/posts/mem1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mahdikhadem.com/posts/mem1/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;On the 18th of Dey(January 8th), at 8:30 p.m., the hospital pavilion was filled with the sound of mothers crying and the wail of ambulance sirens. Blood was running across the floor. Precious young people, groaning in pain, were lying on the ground because there weren’t enough beds.
My friend was shouting at the top of his lungs: “Mehdi… Mehdi!” I couldn’t answer him. I was in shock. I didn’t know what I was doing. My hands were starting to go numb. I kept approximating the wound edges to control the bleeding, but my mind was frozen—almost as if only my cerebellum was giving orders to my hands. My ears were ringing. I was terrified. I had never seen so many young, innocent lives torn apart like that.
As I worked, I kept talking to the boy to make sure he wouldn’t lose consciousness. His name was Amir—one of the kind-hearted kids from Sattar Khan. I tried to joke with him to keep him awake. He was sixteen. He said, “Iran will be free, doctor.” I told him, “Yes—absolutely. That day will come. Don’t doubt it.” I tried to move as fast as I could, because there was still so much more to do, and I didn’t want to put Amir through any more pain than necessary.
Suddenly, my friend—an emergency medicine second-year resident—called out to me. I told Amir, “I’ll be right back,” and ran to the CPR room.
A seventeen-year-old girl was brought in, unconscious and intubated. She had taken a hard blow to the front of her chest—like blunt trauma from a club or something similar. On the other side, her abdomen and chest were covered with multiple stab wounds. One of the injuries was a sucking chest wound. Her heart rate was dangerously low. I started crying—helplessly, uncontrollably—tears streaming down my face. Through blurred, tear-filled eyes, I quickly applied a three-sided occlusive dressing to the sucking wound, but it was too late. Her rhythm kept dropping, lower and lower, with every passing moment.
Someone shouted, “Cleaner—wipe the blood off the floor!”
The cleaner said, “I’ve mopped it so many times… this blood won’t come off.”&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title># TFCE (Threshold‑Free Cluster Enhancement) — Catching the Real Party in a Giant Hotel</title><link>https://mahdikhadem.com/posts/tfce/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mahdikhadem.com/posts/tfce/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Imagine you live in a &lt;strong&gt;huge multi‑story hotel&lt;/strong&gt;. Hundreds of rooms. Every room has people in it, and every room makes &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; noise: talking, TV, a door slam, someone laughing, someone dropping a suitcase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now here’s the problem: you step &lt;strong&gt;outside the hotel&lt;/strong&gt; and you hear &lt;em&gt;party noise&lt;/em&gt; leaking into the street. You want to answer one question:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Which part of the hotel is actually hosting the real party?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In neuroimaging/EEG terms, each “room” can be a &lt;strong&gt;voxel&lt;/strong&gt;, an &lt;strong&gt;electrode&lt;/strong&gt;, or a &lt;strong&gt;time point&lt;/strong&gt;—and the “noise level” is your &lt;strong&gt;test statistic&lt;/strong&gt; (often a &lt;em&gt;t‑value&lt;/em&gt;). Your goal is to locate the true effect without getting fooled by random spikes.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>My Linear Model Thinks Getting Older Makes You Poorer (And Other Statistical Tragedies)</title><link>https://mahdikhadem.com/posts/pitfall/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mahdikhadem.com/posts/pitfall/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;So there I was, building a wage-prediction model like a responsible data scientist, when my Ridge regression dropped a truth bomb that shattered my worldview: &lt;strong&gt;According to my coefficients, every birthday makes you $0.31 poorer per hour.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I immediately canceled my upcoming birthday party and started reverse-aging exercises. Then I remembered: &lt;em&gt;I had fallen into the classic trap of misinterpreting linear model coefficients.&lt;/em&gt; Again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me save you from similar existential crises with a lighthearted tour of coefficient interpretation pitfalls—complete with the statistical equivalent of stepping on a Lego barefoot.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Computer Vision–Based Intraoperative Measurement of Biliopancreatic Limb Length</title><link>https://mahdikhadem.com/projects/project-bpll/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mahdikhadem.com/projects/project-bpll/</guid><description>A pilot study evaluating whether computer vision can replace subjective visual estimation of biliopancreatic limb (BPL) length during gastric bypass surgery with objective, calibrated intraoperative measurements.</description></item><item><title>Diagnostic Delay and Clinical Course of Pemphigus Vulgaris: An Iranian Cohort Study</title><link>https://mahdikhadem.com/projects/project-pemphigus/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mahdikhadem.com/projects/project-pemphigus/</guid><description>A cross-sectional clinical study examining presentation patterns, diagnostic delays, and treatment outcomes in patients with pemphigus vulgaris, highlighting systemic barriers to early diagnosis.</description></item><item><title>Effects of Metabolic and Bariatric Surgery on Serum Uric Acid, Renal Function, and Visceral Adiposity</title><link>https://mahdikhadem.com/projects/project-uricacid/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mahdikhadem.com/projects/project-uricacid/</guid><description>A comprehensive systematic review and meta-analysis examining how metabolic and bariatric surgery (MBS) affects serum uric acid over time, and how these changes relate to renal function and visceral adiposity.</description></item><item><title>M.D. Thesis: Neuroimaging–Cognition Relationships in Frontotemporal Dementia Using Routine Clinical MRI</title><link>https://mahdikhadem.com/projects/project-1/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mahdikhadem.com/projects/project-1/</guid><description>An M.D. thesis project investigating structural neuroimaging correlates of cognitive impairment in frontotemporal dementia (FTD), with a focus on extracting meaningful information from low-resolution routine clinical MRI data.</description></item><item><title>PERSiMED: PERSian Intelligent MEDical Document Reader :A Smart NLP-based Framework for Persian Medical Documents</title><link>https://mahdikhadem.com/projects/project-6/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mahdikhadem.com/projects/project-6/</guid><description>A deep learning–based framework for intelligent extraction, semantic understanding, and structured digitization of Persian medical documents, designed to automate health insurance workflows and fraud detection.</description></item><item><title>Post-Bariatric Weight Trajectory Modelling and Clinical Prediction</title><link>https://mahdikhadem.com/projects/project-weightlosstrajectory/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mahdikhadem.com/projects/project-weightlosstrajectory/</guid><description>A data-driven project that models long-term postoperative weight trajectories after bariatric surgery and translates these patterns into clinically interpretable, patient-level predictions.</description></item><item><title>Retrieval-Augmented Clinical Question Answering for Bariatric Surgery</title><link>https://mahdikhadem.com/projects/project-5/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mahdikhadem.com/projects/project-5/</guid><description>A retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) system that uses the ASMBS bariatric surgery textbook as a knowledge base to answer medical questions with higher accuracy and fewer hallucinations than general-purpose AI models.</description></item><item><title>SnapExplain</title><link>https://mahdikhadem.com/projects/project-7/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mahdikhadem.com/projects/project-7/</guid><description>SnapExplain is an Android utility that brings large language model (LLM) explanations directly into your reading workflow.It integrates with Android’s native text-selection menu, allowing users to highlight any sentence in a PDF, ebook, or article and receive an instant, contextual explanation — without leaving the app they’re reading in.</description></item><item><title>Unveiling Predictors of Hypoalbuminemia Following One Anastomosis Gastric Bypass (OAGB): A Retrospective Analysis</title><link>https://mahdikhadem.com/projects/project-8/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mahdikhadem.com/projects/project-8/</guid><description>A machine learning-based clinical scoring system designed to predict hypoalbuminemia risk following One-Anastomosis Gastric Bypass (OAGB) surgery, enabling early intervention and personalized patient care.</description></item><item><title>How to Build a Hugo Site</title><link>https://mahdikhadem.com/posts/hugo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mahdikhadem.com/posts/hugo/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This article offers a instruction that can be used in to build a Hugo Site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="1-install-hugo-with-winget"&gt;
 1) Install Hugo with winget
 &lt;a class="heading-link" href="#1-install-hugo-with-winget"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fa-solid fa-link" aria-hidden="true" title="Link to heading"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
 &lt;span class="sr-only"&gt;Link to heading&lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Windows PowerShell:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre tabindex="0" class="chroma"&gt;&lt;code class="language-powershell" data-lang="powershell"&gt;&lt;span class="line"&gt;&lt;span class="cl"&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;winget&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;install&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Hugo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="py"&gt;Hugo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="py"&gt;Extended&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hugo’s official Windows install docs explicitly list &lt;code&gt;winget install Hugo.Hugo.Extended&lt;/code&gt; for the extended edition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick check:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre tabindex="0" class="chroma"&gt;&lt;code class="language-powershell" data-lang="powershell"&gt;&lt;span class="line"&gt;&lt;span class="cl"&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;hugo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;version&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id="2-create-a-new-site"&gt;
 2) Create a new site
 &lt;a class="heading-link" href="#2-create-a-new-site"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fa-solid fa-link" aria-hidden="true" title="Link to heading"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
 &lt;span class="sr-only"&gt;Link to heading&lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre tabindex="0" class="chroma"&gt;&lt;code class="language-powershell" data-lang="powershell"&gt;&lt;span class="line"&gt;&lt;span class="cl"&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;hugo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;site&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;site_name&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;That’s the official CLI command for creating a new Hugo site directory.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://mahdikhadem.com/about/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mahdikhadem.com/about/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="-about-me"&gt;
 🙋‍♂️ About Me
 &lt;a class="heading-link" href="#-about-me"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fa-solid fa-link" aria-hidden="true" title="Link to heading"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
 &lt;span class="sr-only"&gt;Link to heading&lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m a medical doctor and data analyst based in Tehran, Iran. I work at the intersection of &lt;strong&gt;clinical medicine and data science&lt;/strong&gt;, focused on applying &lt;strong&gt;AI&lt;/strong&gt; (machine learning, computer vision, NLP/LLMs, predictive modeling, and explainable AI) to improve decision-making and patient outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id="-my-story"&gt;
 🤓 My Story
 &lt;a class="heading-link" href="#-my-story"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fa-solid fa-link" aria-hidden="true" title="Link to heading"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
 &lt;span class="sr-only"&gt;Link to heading&lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My path into medical data science started during my &lt;strong&gt;M.D. thesis&lt;/strong&gt; at &lt;strong&gt;Iran University of Medical Sciences&lt;/strong&gt;, where I studied neuroimaging findings in hospital MRI scans of patients with &lt;strong&gt;frontotemporal dementia (FTD)&lt;/strong&gt; and related them to neuropsychological test scores (e.g., &lt;strong&gt;MoCA&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;MMSE&lt;/strong&gt; and their subdomains). I worked with routine &lt;strong&gt;1.5T low-resolution 2D clinical MRI data&lt;/strong&gt;, used slice-to-volume reconstruction methods, and built analysis pipelines using &lt;strong&gt;FreeSurfer&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;SPM&lt;/strong&gt;. That experience taught me how to handle messy real-world medical data and turn it into evidence.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>ApoE Genotype–Specific Hippocampal Shape Alterations in Alzheimer’s Disease</title><link>https://mahdikhadem.com/projects/project-3/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:33:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mahdikhadem.com/projects/project-3/</guid><description>A neuroimaging study investigating how hippocampal subfield structure and shape differ across ApoE genotypes, using high-resolution MRI and computational geometry–based morphometric analysis.</description></item><item><title>Post-Thesis: Advanced Neuroimaging Analysis Using GenAI</title><link>https://mahdikhadem.com/projects/project-2/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 1970 00:33:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mahdikhadem.com/projects/project-2/</guid><description>An ongoing research effort to improve brain MRI reconstruction techniques, enabling large-scale neurodegeneration studies using routine clinical imaging data rather than relying solely on high-resolution research scans.</description></item><item><title>Contact</title><link>https://mahdikhadem.com/contact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mahdikhadem.com/contact/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>