<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Memories on MahdiKhadem</title><link>https://mahdikhadem.com/categories/memories/</link><description>Recent content in Memories on MahdiKhadem</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mahdikhadem.com/categories/memories/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A tragedy - part 1</title><link>https://mahdikhadem.com/posts/mem1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mahdikhadem.com/posts/mem1/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;On the 18th of Dey(January 8th), at 8:30 p.m., the hospital pavilion was filled with the sound of mothers crying and the wail of ambulance sirens. Blood was running across the floor. Precious young people, groaning in pain, were lying on the ground because there weren’t enough beds.
My friend was shouting at the top of his lungs: “Mehdi… Mehdi!” I couldn’t answer him. I was in shock. I didn’t know what I was doing. My hands were starting to go numb. I kept approximating the wound edges to control the bleeding, but my mind was frozen—almost as if only my cerebellum was giving orders to my hands. My ears were ringing. I was terrified. I had never seen so many young, innocent lives torn apart like that.
As I worked, I kept talking to the boy to make sure he wouldn’t lose consciousness. His name was Amir—one of the kind-hearted kids from Sattar Khan. I tried to joke with him to keep him awake. He was sixteen. He said, “Iran will be free, doctor.” I told him, “Yes—absolutely. That day will come. Don’t doubt it.” I tried to move as fast as I could, because there was still so much more to do, and I didn’t want to put Amir through any more pain than necessary.
Suddenly, my friend—an emergency medicine second-year resident—called out to me. I told Amir, “I’ll be right back,” and ran to the CPR room.
A seventeen-year-old girl was brought in, unconscious and intubated. She had taken a hard blow to the front of her chest—like blunt trauma from a club or something similar. On the other side, her abdomen and chest were covered with multiple stab wounds. One of the injuries was a sucking chest wound. Her heart rate was dangerously low. I started crying—helplessly, uncontrollably—tears streaming down my face. Through blurred, tear-filled eyes, I quickly applied a three-sided occlusive dressing to the sucking wound, but it was too late. Her rhythm kept dropping, lower and lower, with every passing moment.
Someone shouted, “Cleaner—wipe the blood off the floor!”
The cleaner said, “I’ve mopped it so many times… this blood won’t come off.”&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>