<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mehdi Khadem on MahdiKhadem</title><link>https://mahdikhadem.com/authors/mehdi-khadem/</link><description>Recent content in Mehdi Khadem on MahdiKhadem</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mahdikhadem.com/authors/mehdi-khadem/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A tragedy - part 1</title><link>https://mahdikhadem.com/posts/mem1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mahdikhadem.com/posts/mem1/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;On the 18th of Dey(January 8th), at 8:30 p.m., the hospital pavilion was filled with the sound of mothers crying and the wail of ambulance sirens. Blood was running across the floor. Precious young people, groaning in pain, were lying on the ground because there weren’t enough beds.
My friend was shouting at the top of his lungs: “Mehdi… Mehdi!” I couldn’t answer him. I was in shock. I didn’t know what I was doing. My hands were starting to go numb. I kept approximating the wound edges to control the bleeding, but my mind was frozen—almost as if only my cerebellum was giving orders to my hands. My ears were ringing. I was terrified. I had never seen so many young, innocent lives torn apart like that.
As I worked, I kept talking to the boy to make sure he wouldn’t lose consciousness. His name was Amir—one of the kind-hearted kids from Sattar Khan. I tried to joke with him to keep him awake. He was sixteen. He said, “Iran will be free, doctor.” I told him, “Yes—absolutely. That day will come. Don’t doubt it.” I tried to move as fast as I could, because there was still so much more to do, and I didn’t want to put Amir through any more pain than necessary.
Suddenly, my friend—an emergency medicine second-year resident—called out to me. I told Amir, “I’ll be right back,” and ran to the CPR room.
A seventeen-year-old girl was brought in, unconscious and intubated. She had taken a hard blow to the front of her chest—like blunt trauma from a club or something similar. On the other side, her abdomen and chest were covered with multiple stab wounds. One of the injuries was a sucking chest wound. Her heart rate was dangerously low. I started crying—helplessly, uncontrollably—tears streaming down my face. Through blurred, tear-filled eyes, I quickly applied a three-sided occlusive dressing to the sucking wound, but it was too late. Her rhythm kept dropping, lower and lower, with every passing moment.
Someone shouted, “Cleaner—wipe the blood off the floor!”
The cleaner said, “I’ve mopped it so many times… this blood won’t come off.”&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>TFCE (Threshold‑Free Cluster Enhancement) — Catching the Real Party in a Giant Hotel</title><link>https://mahdikhadem.com/posts/tfce/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mahdikhadem.com/posts/tfce/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Imagine you live in a &lt;strong&gt;huge multi‑story hotel&lt;/strong&gt;. Hundreds of rooms. Every room has people in it, and every room makes &lt;em&gt;some&lt;/em&gt; noise: talking, TV, a door slam, someone laughing, someone dropping a suitcase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now here’s the problem: you step &lt;strong&gt;outside the hotel&lt;/strong&gt; and you hear &lt;em&gt;party noise&lt;/em&gt; leaking into the street. You want to answer one question:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Which part of the hotel is actually hosting the real party?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In neuroimaging/EEG terms, each “room” can be a &lt;strong&gt;voxel&lt;/strong&gt;, an &lt;strong&gt;electrode&lt;/strong&gt;, or a &lt;strong&gt;time point&lt;/strong&gt;—and the “noise level” is your &lt;strong&gt;test statistic&lt;/strong&gt; (often a &lt;em&gt;t‑value&lt;/em&gt;). Your goal is to locate the true effect without getting fooled by random spikes.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>My Linear Model Thinks Getting Older Makes You Poorer (And Other Statistical Tragedies)</title><link>https://mahdikhadem.com/posts/pitfall/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mahdikhadem.com/posts/pitfall/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;So there I was, building a wage-prediction model like a responsible data scientist, when my Ridge regression dropped a truth bomb that shattered my worldview: &lt;strong&gt;According to my coefficients, every birthday makes you $0.31 poorer per hour.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I immediately canceled my upcoming birthday party and started reverse-aging exercises. Then I remembered: &lt;em&gt;I had fallen into the classic trap of misinterpreting linear model coefficients.&lt;/em&gt; Again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me save you from similar existential crises with a lighthearted tour of coefficient interpretation pitfalls—complete with the statistical equivalent of stepping on a Lego barefoot.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>How to Build a Hugo Site</title><link>https://mahdikhadem.com/posts/hugo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mahdikhadem.com/posts/hugo/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This article offers a instruction that can be used in to build a Hugo Site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="1-install-hugo-with-winget"&gt;
 1) Install Hugo with winget
 &lt;a class="heading-link" href="#1-install-hugo-with-winget"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fa-solid fa-link" aria-hidden="true" title="Link to heading"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
 &lt;span class="sr-only"&gt;Link to heading&lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Windows PowerShell:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre tabindex="0" class="chroma"&gt;&lt;code class="language-powershell" data-lang="powershell"&gt;&lt;span class="line"&gt;&lt;span class="cl"&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;winget&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;install&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;Hugo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="py"&gt;Hugo&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="py"&gt;Extended&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hugo’s official Windows install docs explicitly list &lt;code&gt;winget install Hugo.Hugo.Extended&lt;/code&gt; for the extended edition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quick check:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre tabindex="0" class="chroma"&gt;&lt;code class="language-powershell" data-lang="powershell"&gt;&lt;span class="line"&gt;&lt;span class="cl"&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;hugo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;version&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id="2-create-a-new-site"&gt;
 2) Create a new site
 &lt;a class="heading-link" href="#2-create-a-new-site"&gt;
 &lt;i class="fa-solid fa-link" aria-hidden="true" title="Link to heading"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
 &lt;span class="sr-only"&gt;Link to heading&lt;/span&gt;
 &lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre tabindex="0" class="chroma"&gt;&lt;code class="language-powershell" data-lang="powershell"&gt;&lt;span class="line"&gt;&lt;span class="cl"&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;hugo&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;site&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;site_name&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;That’s the official CLI command for creating a new Hugo site directory.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>